Inventory of the Lottie V. Clark Papers 1849-1915
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Lottie V. Clark correspondence, 1888-1895. (Box-folder 1:1-5 and 2:1-3)
  - "Cousin," Grace [?], Drewrys Bluff, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 17 January 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Happy to receive Lottie's letter; is afraid she would not recognize her as it has been so long since she has seen her; asks about Christmas; hopes to be able to accept the in-vitation to visit next summer; describes the literary society that she attends; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Susie EM. Eudaily], Duprees, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 7 February 1894., 3 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Apologizes for not writing sooner; describes the Christmas activities.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 20 February 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Describes a recent party; went to town and had her pictures taken; plans to send a piece of cloth from her new dress; her fellow in Georgia has sent his picture; asks if she has received any valentines.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Narnozine, Virginia], 6 March 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Asks about her "fellow"; talks about various friends and family members; includes a short poem.
  - Jacob Lewit, Richmond, Virginia, to L[ottie] V. Clarke [sic], Namozine, Virginia, 24 Mar. 1894., 1 p; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Concerns order of merchandise from Jacob Lewit Dry Goods, Notions and Millinery.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 28 March 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Reports that she is writing while waiting for the Baptist preacher to call; describes a box party for the benefit of the church--"the girls all carried a box filled with something nice to eat. and sold them to the young men...no young man knew whose box he was buying until he had paid for it and then he had to eat what was in the box with the girl..."; reports that her fellow in Georgia has stopped by on his way back to Rhode Island, but she never expects to see him again.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 27 April 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Has been going to church every night; describes two recent weddings; complains that her "looms run so mean."
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 27 May 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Complains that she did not stop for a visit while in Petersburg, [Virginia]; is planning a shopping trip for summer clothes; sends greeting to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 14 August 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Was sorry to hear that she had been sick; went on an excursion to soldiers home-"the prettiest place I ever saw"; reports the death of a man who "has been sick nearly two years."
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia, 31 August 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Has not had any time off from the mill this summer; plans on going on an excursion to Farmville, [Virginia] next month; describes a party--"had plenty of cake, cream, and candy"; sends greetings to various family members.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 20 September 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Happy to hear that she is coming for a visit; expresses surprise that a friend has run away to get married; discusses various church meetings, "the nigroes [sic] have a big meeting about three miles from here-- a crowd goes every night but we have not been yet"; describes visits to Petersburg, [Virginia], Farmville, [Virginia], and "Hampton Sidney (sic] [Hamden-Sydney] College."
  - Anthelia [Holt, Matoaca, Virginia], to Lottie V. Clark, [Namozine, Virginia], 8 October 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Discusses the "protracted[?] meeting"; reports that the heavy rains have interfered with the sowing of her father's oats; talks about the many quiltings around.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 25 November 1894., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Complains of a pain in her shoulder; happy to hear Lottie is coming to visit at Christmas; talks about having the hogs killed and prices on new pigs; discusses winter outfits.
  - Addie Holt, Matoaca P.O., Chesterfield County, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia), 28 January 1895., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Reports that her beau came for a visit; discusses a recent party; complains about the weather; invites her down for a party.
  - Addie Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, to [Lottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 11 February 1895., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Reports that they had to stop work because the weather was so bad; describes "stewing sugar" and "making Bedquilts [sic]"; describes a church meeting where "the Pastor did ever tell us about dancing... ."
  - Anthelia Holt, Matoaca, Virginia, toLottie V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia, 12 February 1895., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Complains of the cold weather--"everything at the mill freezed up"; plans to have a party when the weather warms up, "I want to have cream and cake, candy and Apples ."
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, [Virginia], to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 26 March 1895., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Has been going to church meetings every night; two preachers from Scotland are visiting and "the hail is crowded every night"; reports on two upcoming marriages.
  - Anthelia [Holt], Matoaca, Virginia, to Lottie [V. Clark, Namozine, Virginia], 10 September 1895., 8 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Complains of sore feet; discusses a "baptizing"; describes an attempted elopement; discusses a friend who shot himself; tells of a "splendid sermon"; describes a new "black satteen" dress.
  - Poem, n.d., 4 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Including the names Fannie Robertson and Lottie V. Clarke [sic] written at the end.
  Series 2: Martha Susan Clark and Missouri A. Clark correspondence
- Martha Susan Clark and Missouri A. Clark correspondence, 1849, 1890, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - [?] to Martha Susan Clark, Amelia County, Virginia. Inquires about her health; expresses ardent feelings of love; ends with a poem, 11 September l849[?]., 2 pp. L. Signature clipped. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Inquires about her health; expresses ardent feelings of love; ends with a poem.
  - F[rederick] L. Clark, n.p., to "cousin," M[issouri] A. C[lark], n.p., [?] March 1890., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Apologizes for not being able to visit in the evening because of a toothache; compliments her beauty.
  - Invitation from Mr. D.J. Lewis and Lady to Mrs. Ben Clark [Martha Susan Clark?] and family for December 17 at 6 o'clock p.m., n.d., 1 p; N. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - F[rederick] L. Clark, n.p., to "cousin," M[issouri] A. Clark, n.p., n.d., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Love poem.
  - F[rederick] L. Clark, n.p., to Missouri Clark, Amelia County, Virginia, n.d., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Would like to know her sentiments.
  - F[rederick] L. Clark, n.p., to "cousin," Missouri A. Clark, Amelia County, Virginia, n.d., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Tells her who to send her letters by.
  - Mollie E. Land, n.p., to Missouri A. Clark, Amelia [County, Virginia], n.d., 2 pp; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Has arrived home safely; will send the song by mail; ends with a poem.
  - A[rmistead] B. Spain, n.p., to Missouri [A. Clark], n.p., n.d., 1 p; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Has found her books and sent them to her; asks how she and Mr. C[lark) "are getting along courting" and when they are to be married.
  - Armistead B. Spain, n.p., to Missouri A. Clark, n.p., n.d., 1 p; ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Will deliver her letter privately as requested; is honored by her request to be the "first waiter" on the bride.
  - Armistead B. Spain to Missouri A. Clark, n.d., 3 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Fragments of notes.
  - Poems written to Missouri A. Clark, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Fragments.
  - "The Blue Tailed Fly." With stamped envelope addressed to Miss Missouri A. Clarke [sic], Fords Depot, Dinwiddie County, Virginia, care of R.B. Chaffin, n.d., 1 p. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Poem or song.
  - Subpoena for the Sheriff of Amelia County, Virginia, to summon M[artha] S[usan] Clark, Dibrell S. Clark, J.A. Clark, Frederick S.[sic][L.] Clark "who intermarried with M.A. Clark" and Missouri A. [Clark?], n.d., 1 p; D. (Box-folder 2:4)
  Series 3: Miscellaneous
- Miscellaneous, 1899, 1915. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John M. T[?]ll, n.p., to Judge Thomas Croxton, Tappahannock, Essex County, Virginia, 5 April 1899., 2 pp; ACS. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Gives the address of Dr. W. Saunders as requested by Mr. Garnett.
  - Joseph Stumpf, Manager of Anheuser-Busch Brewing Association, Richmond, Virginia, to [Junius Clark, Amrnon, Virginia), March 1915., 2 items. PM. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Envelopes, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)